Garvit Pahal

g10pahal@gmail.com • +91 8953454203 https://github.com/gpahal • https://linkedin.com/in/gpahal

SUMMARY

Software engineer with 10 years of experience building products 0-1 and beyond. I love working in teams that value excellence, customer delight, and iteration speed. I'm excited about how AI will change our lives and work in the next few years.

EDUCATION

INDIAN INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY (IIT), KANPUR

Kanpur, India

2012 - 2016

- **Bachelor of Technology, Computer Science and Engineering** Cumulative Performance Index (CPI) of 9.6/10
 - Secured All India Rank of 196 in IIT-JEE 2012 (99.97 percentile)

EXPERIENCE

INDEPENDENT SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT AND RESEARCH

Bengaluru, India Aug 2024 - Present

- Built voice customer support agents for B2C finance and quick commerce companies
- Trained a micro GPT model: gpahal/microgpt
- Learning and researching AI

GM LABS Founding Software Engineer

Bengaluru, India

Apr 2022 - Apr 2024

- Built Perch Spotify for reading long-form content, Perch AMA tool for creators, Startup Archive curated startup advice from the world's best founders, gm.xyz a place to host your web3 community
- Architected and led backend and infrastructure. Contributed to the web and mobile apps

HARNESS

Bengaluru, India

Founding Staff Software Engineer

Apr 2019 - Aug 2021

- Harness helps take your code from GitHub to production easily, quickly and resiliently. Made for large enterprises
- Built the workflow engine powering Harness's software delivery platform, supporting durable multi-week workflows
- Helped transition a monolithic app to a microservices deployment, leading to multiple new product launches
- The company grew 50x in revenue and went from a single product to 6

ALPHAGREP SECURITIES

Bengaluru, India Jul 2018 - Mar 2019

Quant Researcher and Trading Analyst

• AlphaGrep is a quantitative trading and investment firm

 Researched and developed high-frequency quantitative trading strategies (linear regression statistical arbitrage) for commodity markets in China, which became my team's most profitable market

DGRAPH

Bengaluru, India Nov 2017 - Jun 2018

Founding Software Engineer

- Dgraph is one of the most popular open-source distributed graph databases
- Launched Ratel, Dgraph's data visualisation and cluster management interface
- Launched database clients in JavaScript and Python. Maintained client libraries for other languages
- Laid groundwork for the Dgraph-as-a-service platform built on top of Kubernetes

PLATO Founder Bengaluru, India

Jul 2015 - Sep 2017

- Plato is a chat app for one-on-one career mentoring
- Conducted successful pilots during college placements and entrepreneurship events
- Funded by Commence Mint. Secured 2nd position in Microsoft Imagine Cup, India (2015) and were incubated at IIT Kanpur

SUPERSTREAM Feb 2022 - Jun 2022

• Superstream is a protocol and a collection of SDKs for real-time money streaming on Solana. It allows anyone to continuously send money to anyone else at any interval up to a second.

- Designed, implemented, and deployed it on devnet, testnet and mainnet clusters of Solana
- The project is open source and documented at <u>superstream.finance</u>

PROGRAMMING TUTORING SYSTEM

Aug 2014 - Oct 2014

- Research project under Dr Sumit Gulwani (Principal Researcher, Microsoft Research, Redmond) and Prof. Amey Karkare (Assistant Professor, IIT Kanpur)
- Launched command line and web apps to assist in teaching introductory programming courses in the 1st year of college by automating assignment and feedback generation and solution-checking
- Project deployed in the 2014-15 academic year (with 400+ enrolled students)

AREAS OF INTEREST

- AI, Databases, Distributed Systems, Programming Languages
- Industries: Developer Tools, Software Infrastructure, Finance, Health, Education, Productivity

AWARDS AND SCHOLASTIC ACHIEVEMENTS

- Received Academic Excellence awards (2013, 2014, 2015) for outstanding performance in academics at IIT Kanpur
- Secured an All India Rank of 196 in the IIT entrance exam in 2012 out of 500,000 applicants (99.97 percentile)
- Qualified for the Indian National Mathematics Olympiad in 2010 and 2011 by securing 2nd and 5th state rank
- Received the prestigious Kishore Vaigyanik Protsahan Yojana (KVPY) from the Department of Science and Technology, Government of India